

# DORIN POTORAC

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

25+ years of experience with enterprise and commercial software web applications. Particularly experienced in React, Next.js and TypeScript. Demonstrated team leading skills and ability to manage all stages of the development lifecycle. Proven track of involvement in successful software releases.

Interested in fully remote frontend developer roles, ideally B2B / core hours 4 AM – 4 PM GMT

**Contact** 

Address

dorin.potorac@gmail.com +40 722 259 246 Dumbrăvița, Timiș ROMANIA

## StackOverflow profile

https://stackoverflow.com/users/502999/dopoto

GitHub profile

https://github.com/dopoto

Blog

https://dopoto.github.io

Portfolio

https://dopoto/github.io/portfolio

LinkedIn profile

https://linkedin.com/in/dorin-potorac-b133208

## **TECH**

#### **Expert**

React, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest, HTML, CSS, Jotai, Figma, JIRA, Git, Confluence

#### **Proficient**

Angular, RxJs, NGRX, Tailwind CSS, Jasmine, Karma, Gatsby, GraphQL, .NET, C#, ASP.NET, Azure, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Google Analytics, Vercel, TeamCity, Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, GitHub Actions/YAML

## **LANGUAGES**

Romanian **native**English **proficient user** 

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

2022 - present Flooz Remote / Permanent

Currently a member of the team developing flooz.xyz – a Next.js Web3 trading platform that allows users to research, buy, sell and swap cryptocurrencies.

- Implemented the backend logic for integrating with various on-ramp providers
- Led the development of the Flooz Trade Widget (flooz/xyz/trade)
- Worked on various integrations (Moonpay, Ramp Network, Transak, Paychant, Mercuryo, Contentful, Dynamic.xyz, Google Analytics, Hotjar, customer.io)
- Contributed to the Next.js pages router app router migration
- Improved CI/CD pipeline scripts (Github Actions, Vercel)

(Next.js, React, TypeScript, Figma, Vercel, Google Cloud Platform)

#### SYSTEM DEVELOPER

2014 – 2022 Visma Software Timișoara, Romania / Permanent

Developed various financial, reporting and BI commercial apps, such as OneStop Reporting – a successful web-based reporting tool with a wide user base. Mostly involved in writing Angular code and unit tests, but also in backend code and DevOps tasks.

(AngularJS / Angular, TypeScript, .NET, SQL Server, MongoDB, C#, Azure)

### PROJECT MANAGER / OPERATIONS MANAGER

2009 – 2014 MK Illumination Deva, Romania / Contract to Permanent

Developed a custom web-based ERP solution designed to handle all the day-to-day operations of the company (managing customers, offers, orders, stocks, supplier orders, deliveries of goods and invoicing). The solution was released in under 5 months and has been used successfully since its initial implementation – the company operates it to handle an average turnover of more than EUR 2M / year.

(ASP.NET, C#, .NET, SQL Server)



# DORIN POTORAC

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

25+ years of experience with enterprise and commercial software web applications. Particularly experienced in React, Next.js and TypeScript. Demonstrated team leading skills and ability to manage all stages of the development lifecycle. Proven track of involvement in successful software releases.

Interested in fully remote frontend developer roles, ideally B2B / core hours 4 AM – 4 PM GMT

Contact Address

dorin.potorac@gmail.com

+40 722 259 246

Dumbrăvița, Timiș ROMANIA

### **SENIOR .NET DEVELOPER**

Sep - Dec 2008 Kynetix London, UK / Contract

I was involved in the development of a .NET 2.0 / SQL Server web application for LIFFE-Euronext, used by various parties involved in coffee and cocoa trading – LIFFE members, warehouse keepers or graders. (ASP.NET, C#, .NET, SQL Server)

#### SENIOR DEVELOPER / MANAGER OF WEB APPS

2007 - 2008 ApexSQL Remote / Permanent

Coordinated ASP.NET 2.0 / SQL Server commercial applications and internal CRM systems. Lead Developer of ApexSQL Report, a popular web-based reporting tool for Microsoft SQL Server.

(ASP.NET, C#, .NET, SQL Server)

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT

#### Apr - Dec 2006 Sutherland Consulting Frankfurt, DE / Contract

Implemented a C# 2.0 / MS SQL Server-based Business Intelligence application for Deutsche Bank. The application was intended to facilitate and support the decision-making needs of senior executives by providing easy access to both internal and external information, relevant to meeting the strategic goals of the organization.

(ASP.NET, C#, .NET, SQL Server)

## **DEVELOPER**

#### 2005 – 2006 Innovative Systems Timișoara, Romania / Permanent

Took part in the development of a leading website generation suite – NetObjects Fusion 9.0. My responsibilities consisted of designing the architectural model and the ASP / ASP.NET framework used by the web components included in the application, and also supervising their implementation, integration and testing processes.

(ASP, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

#### **DEVELOPER**

#### 2000 – 2004 G.E.T. Coder Timisoara, Romania / Permanent

I was involved in the implementation of various digital product stores, shopping carts and credit card payment systems.

(ASP, PHP, JavaScript, SQL Server)



# DORIN POTORAC

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

25+ years of experience with enterprise and commercial software web applications. Particularly experienced in React, Next.js and TypeScript. Demonstrated team leading skills and ability to manage all stages of the development lifecycle. Proven track of involvement in successful software releases.

Interested in fully remote frontend developer roles, ideally B2B / core hours 4 AM – 4 PM GMT

**Contact** Address

dorin.potorac@gmail.com +40 722 259 246 Dumbrăvița, Timiș ROMANIA

# EDUCATION

### **COMPUTER SCIENCES / MATHEMATICS**

**2003 – 2005 Universitatea de Vest** Timișoara, Romania Master's degree. Dissertation: "Security Issues in E-Commerce Applications"

#### **ECONOMICS**

1998 - 2002 Universitatea de Vest Timișoara, Romania

Bachelor's degree. Dissertation: "Electronic Commerce"